A Guide to the Office of the State Librarian Library Board correspondence and subject files, 1964-2009
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Office of the State Librarian Library Board correspondence and subject files, 1964-2009
The Library of Virginia
45050
3.5 cubic feet (10 boxes)
Library of Virginia. Office of the State Librarian.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Accession 45050 transferred by Janice M. Hathcock, Public Information Officer, Library of Virginia, 800 E. Broad Street, Richmond, Virginia, 20 July 2010.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Library Board is made up of 15 members appointed by the Governor to five-year terms. As a policy board, the Library Board is authorized to provide direction to The Library of Virginia with respect to the scope of the Library's collection and its promotion of history education (Code of Virginia, Title 42.1, Chapter 1, Article 1). The board is also responsible for establishing guidelines for the management, preservation, and destruction of the Commonwealth's public records (Code of Virginia, Title 42.1, Chapter 7). The board is authorized to create standards of eligibility for local and regional public library systems regarding the allocation of state and federal funds (Code of Virginia, Title 42.1, Chapter 3), as well as to establish the qualifications required to hold a professional library position in the Commonwealth (Code of Virginia, Title 42.1, Chapter 1, Article 2). The Library Board operates under the supervision of the Secretary of Education.
The Library Board maintains a close working relationship with the State Librarian, agency head of the Library of Virginia. The State Librarian serves as a liaison between the agency, its staff members, and the board. The State Librarian attends board meetings and provides board members with accurate reports on the status of each division of the library. The board is divided into policy and oversight committees based on the internal divisions of the Library of Virginia.
Scope and Content
Contains files for individual Library Board members created and maintained by the State Librarian. The files contain correspondence to and from the board member and other board members, the State Librarian, and administrative personnel. Also included is biographical information, sporadic meeting minutes, attendance information, press releases, resolutions, and certificates of recognition. Many of the files contain notations about the member's years of board service and in some cases, date of death. It is important to note that the dates associated with each member's file do not necessarily correspond with his or her dates of service. Additional material was often added to files after members left the board. In most cases, each file is labeled with the name of the State Librarian who served during that particular member's tenure on the board. The files span the administrations of the following State Librarians: Randolph Church, Donald Haynes, Ella Gaines Yates, John Tyson, and Nolan Yelich. Additions to exisiting files were also made during the tenure of Dr. Sandra Treadway.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into one series, with files arranged alphabetically according to surname. The correspondence is arranged in reverse chronological order.
Contents List
- Series I. Library Board correspondence and subject files, 1964-2009.
  - Berger, Patricia W., 1995. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Berger, Patricia W., 1995. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Berger, Patricia W., 1994. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Berger, Patricia W., 1994. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Berger, Patricia W., 1994. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Berger, Patricia W., 1994. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Berger, Patricia W., 1994. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Berger, Patricia W., 1993. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Berger, Patricia W., 1992-1993. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Berger, Patricia W., 1990-1991. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Berger, Patricia W., 1986-1989. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Bridge, William J., 1990. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Broadbent, Peter E., Jr., Esquire, 1999-2006. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Broadbent, Peter, E., Jr., Esquire, 1998. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Broadbent, Peter E., Jr., Esquire, 1996-1997. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Brooks, A. Gordon, 1969-1996. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Brooks, Ruth Anne M., 1990-2001. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Brooks, Ruth Anne M., 1983-1989. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Butler, Gilbert E., Jr., Esquire, 1999-2006. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Butler, Gilbert E., Jr., Esquire, 1996-1998. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Cabell, Royal E., Jr., 1998-1999. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Cabell, Royal E., Jr., 1996-1998. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Callahan, Dorothy B., 1971-1976. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Clark, Lenwood G., 1997-1999. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Clark, Marjorie M., 1992-2000. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Clarke, Dylyce P., 1997-2005. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Clarke, Dylyce P., 1995-1997. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Cole, Andrew M., 1995-1998. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Cole, Andrew M., 1994. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Cole, Andrew M., 1991-1994. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Cowling, Dr. Dorothy N., 1987-2006. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Cross, Charles B., Jr., 1968-1985. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Cumming, Gwendolyn A., 1993-1997. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Cutler, Kay A., 1991-1996. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Davidson, Carol B., 1993-1998. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Davis, James P., 1986-1991. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Davis, Mary Kathleen B., 1978-1984. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Dietsch, Marjorie, 1973-1980. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Farrier, Augusta Edwards, 1969-1972. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - French, Patricia T., 1974-1985. (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Gravely, Richard P., Jr., 1986-1989. (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Greear, Louella S., 1995-2003. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Guerra, Serf L., 1998-1999. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Guerra, Serf L., 1997-1998. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Guerra, Serf L., 1997. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Guerra, Serf L., 1997. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Guerra, Serf L., 1994-1996. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Harmon, Mary Ann, 2000-2005. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Harmon, Mary Ann, 1998-1999. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Harmon, Mary Ann, 1997-1998. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Harpole, Dr. David H., Sr., 1999-2003. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Haviland, Mary G., 2002-2009. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Hudson, Bobbie B., 1998-2004. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Hudson, Bobbie B., 1994-1997. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Huntley, Hon. William M., 1968-1980. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Jessee, Evans B., Esquire, 1986-2004. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Johnston, F. Claiborne, Jr., Esquire, 1997-2007. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Johnson, Augustus C., 1984-1989. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Johnson, Dr. Lydia J., 2005-2007. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Kearfort, Joseph C., Esquire, 1991-1998. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Kegley, George A., 1972-2006. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Klussman, Dr. Alyce O. Paullin, 1977-2006. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Lawler, Patricia N., 1994-2006. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Levine, Dr. Arlene S., 1990-1991. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Light, R. Chambliss, Jr., 1998-2006. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Lovelace, George E., 2005-2006. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Lozier, Rita Jo Harris, 1983-1989. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - MacDonald, Dr. Edgar E., 1986-2006. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Marshall, Mary A., 1973-1984. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Marshall, Mary A., 1961-1972. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Marston, Christopher M., 1999-2008. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Massenberg, Dr. Samuel E., 2003-2005. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - McCamy, Sharon G., 1998-2003. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - McCutcheon, Andrew H., 1997. (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - McCutcheon, Andrew H., 1995-1996. (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - McCutcheon, Andrew H., 1992-1994. (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Meador, Virginia B. H., 1973-1984. (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Millner, Tyler C., 1996-2000. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Millner, Tyler C., 1995-1996. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Millner, Tyler C., 1992-1995. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Nusbaum, Robert C., 1989-2006. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Nusbaum, Robert C., 1986-1988. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Parker, Jane E., 1997-2001. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Parsons, John W. A., 1986-2006. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Powell, Lewis F., III., Esquire, 2004-2009. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Saunders, W. Marion, 1969-1971. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Ramsey, Dr. Inez L., 1978-1984. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Rickers, Roberta, 1990-2006. (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Roache, M. O., Jr., 1986-1994. (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Roache, M. O., Jr., 1983-1986. (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Robeson, Franklin F., 2000-2005. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Robinson, Dr. Armistead L., 1984-1988. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Rosenberg, Murray D., 1980-2006. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Ryland, Charles H., 1975-1986. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Ryland, Charles H., 1974-1975. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Ryland, Charles H., 1973. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Ryland, Charles H., 1971-1972. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Ryland, Charles H., 1968-1970. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Sadler, Fran M., 1999-2005. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Schrock, Edward L., 1995. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Shackelford, Carroll K., 1977-2000. (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Shackelford, Carroll K., 1971-1974. (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Shackelford, Carroll K., 1964-1971. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Stillman, Margaret P. Forehand, 1990-2002. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Stillman, Margaret P. Forehand, 1986-1988. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Story, Stephen E., Esquire, 2004-2009. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Sutherland, Julia K., 1985-1996. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Sydnor, Wendy C., 1999-2005. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Tate, Robbie G., 1991-1997. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Tarr-Whelan, Keith P., 1987. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Thomas, George W., Jr., 2002-2006. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Thornton, David F., 1982-1996. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Thornton, David F., 1976-1982. (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Walthall, James B., 1994-2006. (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Warden, Hilda Y., 1990. (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Wiencek, Henry, 2003-2009. (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Wilkins, Leona E., 1997-2000. (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Wilkins, Leona E., 1995-1997. (Box 10, Folder 16)